<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on </description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Confining Strings, Infinite Statistics and Integrability</title>
      <link>/publications/quonintegrability/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/quonintegrability/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h4 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We study confining strings in massive adjoint two-dimensional chromodynamics. Off-shell, as a consequence of zigzag formation, the resulting worldsheet theory provides a non-trivial dynamical realization of infinite quon statistics. Taking the high energy limit we identify a remarkably simple and novel integrable relativistic $N$-body system. Its symmetry algebra contains an additional &amp;ldquo;shadow&amp;rdquo; Poincar&amp;#233; subalgebra. This model describes the $N$-particle subsector of a $T\bar{T}$-deformed massless fermion.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adjoint QCD in D=2</title>
      <link>/research/adjointqcd2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/adjointqcd2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Integrable models are uniquely simple physical systems with a sufficient number of conserved quantities to trivialize their dynamics. This means that they are exactly solvable, a rare thing even in classical mechanics. They also hide in quantum field theories where their solvability can uplift to give us important toy models, which allow us to ask questions that would be difficult to approach otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We obtained this model as the high energy limit of adjoint QCD in two dimensions. When the dynamics are solved for in the &lt;em&gt;Mathematica&lt;/em&gt; file above, it is clear that the system is integrable as the initial and final sets of momenta are the same. Notice that the particles have identity (colors above), but that asympotically they have a preferred ordering. Both the line and circle geometries are available in the above code. Enjoy playing around!&lt;/p&gt;




  




&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;/img/compactscatter.gif&#34; &gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From QCD Strings to WZW</title>
      <link>/publications/qcdtowzw/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/qcdtowzw/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h4 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the Axionic String Anstaz (ASA) confining flux tubes in pure gluodynamics are in the same equivalence class as a new family of integrable non-critical strings, called axionic strings. In addition to translational modes, axionic strings carry a set of worldsheet axions transforming as an antisymmetric tensor under the group of transverse rotations. We initiate a study of integrable axionic strings at general number of space-time dimensions $D$. We show that in the infinite tension limit worldsheet axions should be described by a peculiar &amp;ldquo;pseudofree&amp;rdquo; theory-their $S$-matrix is trivial, but the corresponding action cannot be brought into a free form by a local field redefinition. This requirement fixes the axionic action to take a form of the $O(D−2)$ Wess-Zumino-Witten (WZW) model.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
